this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at se - radio dotnet
si radio brings you relevant detailed
discussions about software engineering
topics at least once a month
thanks to our audience and the partners
listed on our website for supporting the
podcast
[Music]
hello everybody to a new episode of se
radio this is going to be a somewhat
different episode you're not going to
have fun of our typically interviews
today rather we have what we typically
call a state of the union well I think
people have complained about that so
state of se radio episode and with me on
the Skype connection or me Hale and
multi envelope hello
well and big changes are coming in se
radio I think I I mentioned something
without saying what on in it on or tweet
a while ago when we celebrated our five
millionth download and in you know doing
it just like Apple does it I'm not going
to say yet what's going to change but
well you might have read it in the title
of the episode but that we're first
going to look at what se Radio has
achieved in the last couple of years we
have 182 episodes today I think in total
more than five million downloads but I
think it's a pretty amazing number I
never thought that it would be so high
until I read your I read your tweet
really amazing I think yeah we have
today we have typically about two or
three thousand downloads per day in
total and when I look back over the past
I don't know maybe six years now
could they be is that right yeah yeah
well the past six years its I'm pretty
happy that we we get so many great and
interesting interview partners invited
to our show it's it was always fun and a
lot of a lot of great stuff to to talk
to people like I know Martin Fowler and
Ken bag and all the others it was really
a lot of fun yeah I agree I agree
and so I we have the the best downloaded
episodes that just checked a minute ago
had 47,000 something and downloads and
on average we have about 20 7500 so
that's quite a sizable reasonable
audience I think the best one yeah the
best one was the patterns episode we did
at the very beginning it may be that
because it's the first episode people
downloaded it automatically when this
you know subscribe to the podcast so
maybe that's the reason maybe it's also
just a great
but there are also a number of others
with more than 40,000 actually why don't
I briefly check what the top ten are
they'll be interesting yeah let me check
so who wants to do a bet on it well I
don't know I would guess that actually I
had no idea and I think the episode with
Vanna for goods is among the top ten
okay I believe Doug Smith could be high
up in the top ten
I'm going to venture that some of the
more recent episodes probably would be
in the top ten if there weren't so
reason I mean obviously you can't have
you know that the latest episode with
with some of the most downloads
obviously so let me let me read the top
ten to you starting with one two three
four five six seven eight nine ten so
ten is living architectures I think that
was with Andre why not right yeah 36,000
then we have 36,000 something we have
the dependencies episode that's episode
number two and then next best is the
being a consultant episode was also one
of the first episode where we didn't do
any editing yeah yeah because that was
the quietest place we could find in
Hamburg okay so the next one was episode
170 with bus for a what what was the
topic there there was a Jilla d in the
large I see okay then the next one is
the Scala update with Martin o turski
with it or not too long ago was 171 so
then the next one is feature indeed
software development part 2 38,000 and
then Kent back with 40,000 then next one
is memory great architectures with
40,000 and then what do you think
actually there is like that already so
don't know there is a way to find it to
find out what this one is
it's actually
of obvious no seriously because we've
already had the power to of the feature
oriented software development right okay
and then episode on the first place is
the patterns episode so um well I guess
before we announced the changes we
should say thank you to all the people
who who are and were involved especially
those that are not so visible because
they work in the background right yeah
so um I started with our spam fighter
it's a Tina McCauley ballet right so he
moderates the comments and you know
kills the crap very useful we didn't
have an automatic spam filter but it
doesn't work well so he does the rest
then we have our publishing crew there
is fog of more stuff who you know
collects all the show notes and stuff
and then puts the stuff online for
download and that was Kristie Popovich
II who does the sound editing so we
basically sent him the raw the raw
edited interviews and he then puts on
you know that the sound and our our
channel at the beginning he cleans up
some of the audio and there's a web
administrator been called right here a
long long friend of us things banned
very much I think he at some point also
did an episode but I think only one or
two maybe no I don't remember exactly
yeah yes forever I think maybe long the
beginning is think so yeah yeah it's
funny I always thought that you were on
the team since the beginning but that's
not true right WX conference in Munich I
don't know many years ago when you asked
me if I would like to join the team so
that existed before hmm well since we're
talking about the old times there are
three editors who have left us since
then indeed I think I think all of them
were founding editors ever hot wolf who
you know as mr. spring who no that's
something different but he still talks
about spring all the time no no ha and
Alexander Schmitt they have all left us
because they basically didn't have any
time anymore but thank you folks again
thanks for pushing in the beginning so
hard yeah absolutely it's always
important to get you know to get a good
group at the beginning to get something
launched and we should also thank our
new editors who have done a couple of
episodes already and you who you know by
voice probably min and Scott Jenson and
they have you know taken up some of the
slack that that we created kind of doing
episodes and that kind of the holes that
opened up when ever half unalloyed Alex
left and I think they brought in a quite
a somewhat different you know you know
set of topics but that's very used very
useful because we don't so we don't you
know do the same stuff all the time
very good so should we talk about the
change yes so the change is that from
now on as a radio will live under the
wings or under the umbrella of I Triple
E software and actually there is another
person on our conference call here he
didn't say anything so far so welcome
Forrest ciao thank you
hi it's great to be here good to have
you on so you're going to be well why
don't you introduce yourself so so
people know who you are sure well I'm
the editor-in-chief of I Triple E
software magazine and actually I maybe I
should begin by saying actually I've
been a big fan of SD radio for a long
time so we're looking into this new
relationship we're moving into this new
relationship with a sense of both being
very excited I think this is a great se
radio I think it's done a great job and
it's just exciting to be associated with
it and you know a little tiny bit of
nervousness also because I think that
when you have something that has such a
great cachet and has such a loyal
listener ship you don't want to do
anything that's going to mess any of
that up so we really we recognize that
we have big shoes to fill but we're very
excited and I think this is a great
partnership that we can go forward with
yeah
so do you want to say a little bit about
the magazine and you know how how that
fits as your radio yes I'd love to
so I Triple E software is one of the
leading magazines in
for engineering and one of the unique
things about this is that we have a mix
of articles that are both peer-reviewed
so that have been vetted rigorously and
have gone through the scientific peer
review process we really do take it
quite seriously our mission to try and
take things that are in research that
piece should be being used by people in
industry and by practitioners and make
sure that their practitioners are
getting the best advice and the best
findings from the research but we also
have a number of other features in the
magazine some departments for example
that are written by a lot of the thought
leaders in the field so we have pieces
that are written by Grady Booch for
example on an ongoing basis
we have Phillipe Christian who's writing
some of the more thought-provoking a
more controversial columns and trying to
get some debate and discussion started
about that so we have a long history of
trying to be on the cutting edge our
mission is to be the best possible
source of reliable useful and
peer-reviewed information for
practitioners and I think that the the
way that we've tried to have coverage
the way that we've tried to keep people
that read the magazine up-to-date on the
topics that they need to know about the
state current in this software
engineering field which is changing all
the time I think that these mission
statements that we have in the success
that we've had is it goes exactly in the
same direction as what se radio has been
able to do all these years also yeah I
think one way I always phrased it is
that I Triple E is trying to also be
hype free and not be too much driven by
you know that the topic of the day but
rather a little bit more by the you know
timeless fundamentals in some sense and
as you radio has always tried to do that
as well yes so I'm so glad you said that
actually because we do I mean there's no
shortage of hype and and all kinds of
very sad driven types of information out
there and we really do try and cut
through all of that and come up with
like you said what's been tested and
what's proven and what do people really
need to know about and like you said I
think we recognize a kindred spirit in
the se radio team yeah I think we should
we should say a word about how we got to
the point of of doing this so I have
been on the editorial board
for the last I think three years I've
just been rotated out and that's how I
got to know the the I Triple E software
and and there was at one board meeting
in Munich there was a discussion about
you know new media in multimedia and how
I totally software could become more
modern and you know in terms of that the
media and not not in terms of the
content and I and I was thinking well
that that sounds like they should do a
podcast and that I was a starting point
for the thing right yes it's just it's
amazing to me I think that um for a long
time I think there was this kind of a
sense that Louis we're doing very
rigorous and peer-reviewed information
that there's a sense in which it's meant
to be in a written publication and I
think over the last few years we've
really worked very hard with the other
folks at the magazine to change that
perspective and I think that the more we
can do to reach practitioners in all the
ways that they can best use the
information the better off we're going
to be and the more the bigger audience
we're going to be able to reach right
and what I always say is I live in
Washington DC which means I live a huge
percentage of my time I think spent on
the Beltway they have the big highway
that goes around the city stuck in
traffic and if it wasn't for things like
SC radio it would just be wasted time
but as it turns out it's time where I
feel like oh I can get caught up on all
those past episodes I really wanted to
hear about right so I think it's a great
way to kind of get get the information
to people where they can most use it in
their in their ongoing alive right so
let's talk about what is not going to
change as a consequence of this of this
merger or whatever you want to call it
well one thing I was going to say with
some we're going to be very careful not
to change is the the wide variety of
topics that have been covered on SB
radio I think one reason that I Triple E
software is a good fit is that in every
issue we do make sure that we have
coverage over all the major activities
and requirements architecture design
testing development all the technologies
that are both technical and and human
aspects related so I think that one
thing I've always enjoyed about SC radio
is that there's such a broad array of so
many kinds of
topics you know ranging all the way from
individual programming languages to
things like quantum computing and I
think that we're really going to put the
effort into making sure that we keep
that broad spectrum of things that all
kinds of different people are going to
be able to find topics that they're
really interested in and excited about
with things going forward yeah I think
it's it's very important to hear that as
the radio will remain on the Creative
Commons Licence right so it's it will
still be free to listen and to be free
to consume for all our listeners the
past episodes the future episodes will
all be all be the same right yeah
absolutely right that there is also not
going to be any advertisement on the
shows except maybe you know cross hints
you know the magazine may say here is an
interesting episode and as your radio
and as your radio may say here is an
interesting article that you may read if
you were interested in any deeper right
mm-hmm exploit the benefits off of this
yes I certainly hope that listeners will
not hear any kind of a big change in the
tone or in the you know we certainly
wait you know we're not out there being
marketing type people you know we really
are a bunch of technical and technical
folks technical geeks I was going to say
much more interested in the content than
about selling things right so what's
going to change is that well what is
going to change first of all I guess
there will be new people on the team
right first you're going to be the how
would you call it the spiritual leader I
think one of the things that will be
changing is that there's going to be a
lot of new voices that listeners will be
hearing and like I said we have your
experts associated with the magazine
that have all kinds of different topic
areas that they're interested in and
we'll be rotating through a lot of these
folks you know every every one of them
has access to a lot of the thought
leaders in the field and a lot of the
interesting new things coming out of
either research and innovative practice
and so I think that my hope is that
we're going to rotate among all these
different topic areas and you'll be
hearing a number of different voices
talking about the the topics that you
know they're they're really passionate
about so we do have a large editorial
board and we'll be a
to exploit that I think going forward to
make sure that we do get exciting topics
from a lot of these different areas
right right
I guess that the of course there were
also some of the current team will also
stay on I know that Attila has already
announced that he will continue to fight
spam what about you guys
multimeter yeah I will definitely stay
on the team and I will also introduce
some episodes maybe not not you know or
maybe in the past I was also not a very
frequent speaker on a radio so I didn't
record that many episodes but I will
definitely continue to record episodes
pharisee radio and will continue to stay
on the team the same holds true for me I
also intend to do the one and the other
episode here and there
uninteresting topics on on topics that I
catch up during my daily job and and
like to share and talk about in this
broader forum right so same for me here
although I think in the in the near
future you won't hear much of me I'm
quite busy with my my other podcast the
Omega tar thing which I have to grow to
the same numbers as your radio we're
still far away so I'm going to focus on
that in the near future but I'm sure I'm
going to do the occasional se radio
episode of course as well so what else
do we have to say what did we miss what
did we forget I guess we're all I hope I
can certainly say that I'm looking
forward quite a bit to this to this
cooperation and I'm and I'm really I
really think this is going to be you
know a very fruitful cooperation in the
sense that that I mean I know some of
the people have had Tripoli software and
I know that that's a fit yes okay so
you've had I think several of our board
members actually as interviewees on
podcasts over the course of the last
year or so so um it'll be I think we'll
be able to tap those people and go back
to them and hear some more about what
they've been doing and it will be
interesting to have them on the other
side of the microphone yes right yeah
absolutely
I'm definitely forward to it
very excited I mean about this change
about well the fresh blood about the new
voices about new additional topics no I
I like it
yeah I think we are looking forward into
a great future for se radios I'm very
much looking forward to it I'm really
excited about this cooperation really
great so one last thing that should
hopefully not be any like infrastructure
changes the URL should still work it
might redirect to another page the the
URL for the podcast we've already routed
it through Feedburner so that should
work continue to work as well even if we
decided to host the show somewhere else
which at this point we haven't decided
yet so most likely the the
infrastructure that's visible to you
guys sutra duty to listeners shouldn't
change but if it if it does change will
will let you know of course by the way
yeah
Martine we have forgotten to thank
somebody before we didn't thank our
listeners we should should do this of
course to the five million
we always not five million people it's
five million downloads but two thousand
fifty thousand approximately it's
probably realistic thank you thank you
and and tell your friends so we can add
another fifty thousand yes please okay
so um then I guess that's it so but let
me say one more time just thank you well
those to the listeners and to you guys
for putting so much energy and building
up such an exciting and a viable podcast
I think like I said we're really looking
forward to taking it forward and you
know even building on what you've done
and certainly taking it further
hopefully it was a lot of fun I can say
that I mean it really was a labor of
love and and and we were certainly very
happy to see where it has gone and and
also to see it now taken over by by an
established organization that you know
keeps it alive and until the indefinite
future okay so great thank you and bye
right
thanks for listening to software
engineering radio as a radio is an
educational program brought to you by
hillside Europe if you want more
information about the podcast and the
other episodes visit our website at se -
radio dotnet if you want to support us
you can donate to the SA radio team via
the website or you can advertise for SA
radio for example by clicking on the
Digg reddit delicious and slash dog
buttons or by talking about us on
Twitter and Facebook you can also
support us by joining team and
shouldering some of the work to contact
the team please send email to team at se
- radio net or if your feedback is
specific to an episode please use the
comments facility on the website so
other people can react to your comments
this episode of se radio as well as all
other episodes are licensed under a
creative commons 2.5 license please see
the website for details
[Music]